<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
<eadheader audience="internal" findaidstatus="complete" langencoding="iso639-2b">
	<eadid encodinganalog="856$u">UAMS269</eadid>
  <filedesc>
	 <titlestmt> 
		<titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Southwest Environment Service
		  records, 
		  <date>1975-1988</date></titleproper>
		<author encodinganalog="245$c">Inventory prepared by Roger Myers</author>
	 </titlestmt>
	 <publicationstmt>
	 	<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</publisher> 
		<address>
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline>
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline>
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline>
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address>
		<date>2001</date> 
		<p>Arizona Board of Regents. All Rights Reserved.</p>
	 </publicationstmt> 
  </filedesc> 
  <profiledesc>
	 <creation encodinganalog="500">Finding aid encoded by Jan Marie Payne 
		<date>October 3, 2001</date></creation> 
	 <langusage>Finding aid is in<language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English.</language></langusage> 
  </profiledesc> 
<revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-06-20">2017-06-20</date><item>This finding aid was updated in alignment with LC EAD 2.0 specifications using a python script created by Erik Radio.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader> 
<frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
	 <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Southwest Environment Service records, 
		<date>1975-1988</date></titleproper>
	 <num>Collection Number: MS 269</num>
  	<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</publisher>
	 <list>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Processed by:</label>
		  <item>Roger Myers</item>
		</defitem>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Date completed:</label>
		  <item>
			 <date>1988</date></item>
		</defitem>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Encoded by:</label>
		  <item>Jan Marie Payne</item>
		</defitem>
	 </list>
	 <p>© 2001. Arizona Board of Regents. All rights reserved.</p>
  </titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc encodinganalog="351$c" level="collection"> 
  <did>
	 <head>Collection Summary</head>
	 <unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Collection Name">Southwest
		Environment Service records, 
		<unitdate normal="1975/1988" type="inclusive">1975-1988</unitdate></unittitle>
	 <unitid countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099" label="Collection Number" repositorycode="US-azu"> MS 269</unitid> 
	 <origination label="Creator"> 
		<corpname encodinganalog="110">Southwest Environmental
		  Service</corpname></origination>
	 <abstract label="Abstract">The records contain a comprehensive view of one of the most
		important environmental advocacy groups in Arizona from 1974 until
		1988.</abstract>
	 <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Physical Description"><extent encodinganalog="300">5.8 linear feet</extent></physdesc>
	 <repository label="Repository">
	 	<corpname encodinganalog="110">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</corpname>
		<address>
		  <addressline>University of Arizona</addressline>
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline>
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline>
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline>
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address></repository>
  </did> 
  <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
	 <head>Restrictions</head>
	 <p>None.</p>
  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
	 <head>Copyright</head>
	 <p>It is the responsibility of the user to obtain permission to publish
		from the owner of the copyright (the institution, the creator of the record,
		the author or his/her transferees, heirs, legates, or literary executors). The
		user agrees to indemnify and hold harmless the Arizona Board of Regents for the
		University of Arizona, its officers, employees, and agents from and against all
		claims made by any person asserting that he or she is an owner of
		copyright.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
	 <head>Credit Line</head>
	 <p>Southwest Environment Service records(MS 269).Special Collections, University of Arizona Libraries.</p>
  </prefercite>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="545"> 
	 <head>Historical Note</head>
	 <p>Southwest Environmental Service (SES) was a non-profit organization
		working for the protection of the environment, including air quality, water
		quality, and land planning. It was incorporated on 4 November 1974, and funded
		by the Wilson Foundation to "help the public share in finding solutions to
		environmental problems." In 1984, it became a "public charity" and was now
		eligible to devote 20% of its resources to lobbying.</p> 
	 <p>Through public education, mailings, lobbying, workshops, publications,
		and legal actions, the SES worked with public and government agencies to
		maximize its goals of a more desirable environment for Arizona and of citizen
		input into governmental processes. Major projects in which the SES was involved
		included the establishment of Catalina State Park (1975-1981), Aviation
		Corridor Highway (1985), groundwater and wastewater regulations (1976-1983),
		and smelter advocacy (1979-1987). </p>
	 <p>SES's first director was David Hoyt. Priscilla Robinson became the
		second director on 1 April 1975, and continued in that position until the
		agency closed in March 1988. The records of SES were culled by Ms. Robinson and
		donated to the University of Arizona Library. Original folder headings were
		retained in the inventory where possible.</p>
  </bioghist> 
  <arrangement> 
	 <head>Organization</head> 
	 <p>This collection is organized into five series:</p> 
	 <list> 
		<item>Series I: Director's Reports and Board of Director's Meetings
		  Minutes, 
		  <date>1975-1987</date></item> 
		<item>Series II: Correspondence and Testimonies, 
		  <date>1977-1980</date></item>
		<item>Series III: Publications, 
		  <date>1977-1988</date></item> 
		<item>Series IV: Photographs, 
		  <date>1986</date></item> 
		<item>Series V: Workshops and Projects, 
		  <date>1975-1988</date></item> 
	 </list> 
  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="520"> 
	 <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
	 <p>The records contain a comprehensive view of one of the most important
		environmental advocacy groups in Arizona from 1974 until 1988. The director's
		monthly reports and correspondence document the interests and direction of the
		agency, its' position on issues in Arizona, its' relationship to other state
		and national environmental groups, and to a lesser extent, public reaction to
		its proposals and activities. The correspondence and testimonies provide
		insight into the daily communications between SES and public officials and
		private citizens. As a speaker for concerned citizens, SES provided an
		alternative viewpoint on the environmental impact and assessment of issues
		involving land-use planning, water and air quality, and pollution from
		industrial sources.</p> 
	 <p>The publications of SES in this collection contain a representative
		sample of the flyers, brochures, and updates prepared and distributed by the
		staff. Substantial reports, often prepared as a final product of a grant, are
		present; selected titles include 
	 <title>Water Workshops Workbook</title>, 1977; 
	 <title>Water Resources of the Tortolita Area</title>, 1977; 
	 <title>Blue Skies: An Arizonan's Guide to Clean Air</title>, 1980; 
	 <title>Flood and Erosion Hazards in Tucson</title>, 1980; and a draft of 
	 <title>Chemicals Used in the Mining Process: Their Potential Threats to
		Ground Water</title>, 1984.</p>
	 <p>Three photographs portray Priscillia Robinson at work on the Governor's
		Water Quality Task Force, at the signing of the Environmental Quality Act of
		1986 by Governor Bruce Babbitt, and with fellow activists Dick Kamp and Bob
		Yuhnke.</p>
	 <p>The bulk of the records relate to short-term workshops given by SES and
		in-depth projects of local and state concern, especially advocacy directed at
		protecting the people and resources of Arizona and the West from air and water
		pollution by land development and copper smelting. One of their earliest
		projects concerned the establishment and stewardship of the Catalina State
		Park, located on the northwestern slopes of the Santa Catalina Mountains
		outside of Tucson. Working with local groups like the Catalina State Park
		Coalition, county supervisors, legislators, and developers, SES helped secure
		the lands for the park from the possibility of subdivision and development.
		After years of negotiations, state budgetary uncertainties, and a series of
		complicated land exchanges and lease agreements with Pima County and Arizona
		State Parks the park was finally dedicated on May 25, 1983. Extensive clippings
		and printed materials highlight the history of the creation of the park.</p>
	 <p>Together with the Southern Arizona Environmental Council, and funded by
		a grant from the U.S. Office of Education, SES offered workshops to facilitate
		discussions and to increase public understanding of the Tortolita Mountain Area
		and Pima County Planning Department's proposed land-use plan for that over 200
		square mile area located northwest of Tucson. These files contain
		correspondence, reports, and printed materials relative to the planning,
		contents, and results of meetings held in October 1975 to project the future of
		a rapidly growing area of a sunbelt city.</p>
	 <p>In June 1976, SES received a grant from the U.S. Office of Education to
		conduct a series of public workshops in 1977 on Tucson's water supply. SES
		contracted to gather demographic information on participants, to evaluate the
		effectiveness of process-oriented methods used, and to manage a follow-up
		survey after the workshops were completed. A final report contains survey,
		description, and analysis of the grant. The 
	 <title>Water Workshops Workbook</title> used in the meetings is present in
	 the Publications series.</p>
	 <p>There are several folders on the Sabino Creek issue which required Pima
		County to bring its' Mt. Lemon Wastewater Treatment Plant into compliance with
		federal regulations. Represented by David S. Baron of Arizona Center for Law in
		the Public Interest, SES initiated a lawsuit to force the county to abide by
		standards established for the treatment of existing and prospective wastes
		which were targeted for discharge into the creek. This case was one of several
		in this collection in which SES and Center for Law in the Public Interest
		worked together in common cause.</p>
	 <p>To encourage citizen participation in the planning process for state
		implementation plans for the federal Clean Air Act, SES, in conjunction with
		several other interested groups, presented a Clean Air Workshop in 1978.
		Sponsored by a U.S. Environmental Protection Agency grant, the workshop
		provided overviews of the existing laws, presentations on selected areas of
		interest by experts, and meetings of action planning groups. A publication, 
	 <title>Blue Skies</title>, is present in the Publication series.</p>
	 <p>Another significant issue in these records is the water quality
		legislation which resulted in the landmark Environmental Quality Act, signed
		into law by Arizona governor Bruce Babbitt in 1986. Ms. Robinson was a
		contributing member of the Water Quality Task Force, a panel appointed by the
		governor to resolve conflicting opinions on the bill as it was being drafted.
		The act, heralded as a model for protecting water resources in the West,
		appointed agencies to protect surface and ground water supplies, set provisions
		for enforcing the statutes, established a Superfund to clean up hazardous waste
		sites, and changed the system of regulating pesticide use in Arizona. </p>
	 <p>In 1980 and 1981, SES presented another community information program to
		help citizens examine local flood plain management policies. Consisting of a
		published sourcebook, five workshops, audiovisual presentations, and other
		outreach methods, this project raised local awareness of flood and erosion
		hazards in southern Arizona. A final report to the sponsoring agency, National
		Science Foundation, provided written and visual summations of the grant. A
		final draft of Barbara Tellman's 
	 <title>Flood and Erosion Hazards in Tucson</title> are is in the
	 Publication series.</p>
	 <p>The remainder of the records relate to the most important issues
		addressed by SES - copper industry in Arizona and Mexico, smelter advocacy, and
		related air quality and acid rain concerns. SES was actively involved in
		monitoring the non-ferrous smelter orders (NSOs) for Phelps Dodge's Douglas
		smelter and Magma Copper Company's San Manuel smelter, and in formulating
		positions on international agreements to protect environmental elements in the
		so-called "Grey Triangle" - an area bounded by the Douglas smelter and two
		large Mexican-owned smelters in Cananea and Nacozari, Sonora. </p>
	 <p>Of note also are files relating to SES's efforts to force the federal
		government to bring Phelps Dodge and Magma facilities into compliance with the
		Clean Air Act. Through petitions, hearings, and lawsuits involving SES,
		Environmental Defense Fund, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Arizona
		Department of Health Services, and other agencies, the Douglas smelter was
		closed, and Magma built a new, cleaner furnace.</p>
	 <p>The shift from advocacy of land-use planning and water quality to issues
		of urban and rural air quality and smelter emission control is documented in
		these records. The use of the legislative and legal process to create and
		enforce state and federal standards is evident in the Sabino Creek,
		Environmental Quality Act, and smelter advocacy files. Due to a lack of
		prospective large projects, a lessening of grant support, and a decision by
		SES's director to direct her professional attentions to other fields, SES
		ceased operation on 31 March 1988, thus ending 14 years of responsible
		leadership and informed commentary of many environmental issues facing Tucson,
		Arizona, and the West.</p>
  </scopecontent> 
  <controlaccess>
	 <persname>Babbitt, Bruce E.</persname><persname>Baron, David S.</persname><persname>Kamp, Richard</persname><persname>Tellman, Barbara</persname><persname> Yuhnke, Robert E.</persname><corpname>United States -- Environmental
			 Protection Agency</corpname><corpname>Pima County (Ariz.) -- Wastewater
			 Management Dept.</corpname><corpname>Smelter Crisis Education
			 Project</corpname><corpname>Arizona Center for Law in the Public
			 Interest</corpname><corpname>Phelps Dodge
			 Corporation</corpname><corpname>Magma Copper Company</corpname><corpname>Groups Against Smelter
			 Pollution</corpname><corpname>Environmental Defense
			 Fund</corpname><subject>Environmental policy -- Arizona</subject><subject>Water quality -- Arizona</subject><subject>Air - Pollution -- Arizona</subject><subject>Water-supply -- Arizona</subject><subject>Flood control -- Arizona -- Tucson</subject><subject>Acid rain -- Arizona</subject><subject>Copper mines and mining -- Arizona</subject><subject>Smelting -- Environmental aspects -- Arizona</subject><subject>Environmental protection -- Arizona -- Citizen
			 participation</subject><subject>Public interest law -- Arizona</subject><subject>Land use -- Arizona -- Planning -- Citizen
			 participation</subject><geogname>Catalina State Park (Ariz.)</geogname><geogname>Tortolita Mountains Region (Ariz.)</geogname><geogname>Arizona -- Politics and government</geogname><geogname>Grey Triangle Region (Ariz.-Mexico)</geogname><genreform>Correspondence</genreform><genreform>Photographs</genreform><genreform>Minutes</genreform><genreform>Records</genreform><genreform>Testimonials</genreform></controlaccess> 
  <dsc type="combined"> 
	 <head>Container List</head>
	 <c01 level="series">
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Series I: Director's Reports and Board of Director's
			 Meetings Minutes, 
			 <unitdate normal="1975/1988" type="inclusive">1975-1988</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Contains monthly director's reports outlining the current
			 activities, including workshops planned, hearings attended, and new issues to
			 the Board of Directors; agendas of meetings; and minutes of meetings.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<c02 level="file">
		  <did><container id="c04d1dc7-8800-49c3-b0e7-80d277815492" type="box">1</container><container parent="c04d1dc7-8800-49c3-b0e7-80d277815492" type="folder">1</container>
			 <unittitle>Board of Directors roster. 
				<unitdate normal="1979/1984" type="inclusive">1979-1984</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="file">
		  <did><container id="39efa4fc-2876-42f4-aaae-a57492a70377" type="box">1</container><container parent="39efa4fc-2876-42f4-aaae-a57492a70377" type="folder">2-9</container>
			 <unittitle>Director's reports and Board minutes. 
				<unitdate normal="1975/1987" type="inclusive">1975-1987</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		</c02>
	 </c01> 
	 <c01 level="series">
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Series II: Correspondence and Testimonies, 
			 <unitdate normal="1977/1987" type="inclusive">1977-1987</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Contains incoming letters, and photocopies of outgoing office
			 replies, on a wide variety of issues and information requests. The bulk of the
			 correspondence is between government officials and the director and research
			 assistants at SES. Also includes typescripts and drafts of testimony given by
			 the director and staff at public hearings in Tucson, Phoenix, and Washington,
			 DC. Correspondents include Arizona politicians Dennis DeConcini, Morris Udall,
			 Jim Kolbe, and Bruce Babbitt. Additional correspondence is found in the
			 Workshops and Projects series.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<c02 level="file">
		  <did><container id="195b7dbc-38b5-4c49-8018-00f3a89bd747" type="box">1</container><container parent="195b7dbc-38b5-4c49-8018-00f3a89bd747" type="folder">10</container>
			 <unittitle>Correspondence and testimonies. 
				<unitdate normal="1977/1980" type="inclusive">1977-1980</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="file">
		  <did><container id="b2fc5274-e649-4f94-ba20-30cb9223b360" type="box">2</container><container parent="b2fc5274-e649-4f94-ba20-30cb9223b360" type="folder">1-6</container>
			 <unittitle>Correspondence and testimonies. 
				<unitdate normal="1981/1987" type="inclusive">1981-1987</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		</c02>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="series">
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Series III: Publications, 
			 <unitdate normal="1977/1988" type="inclusive">1977-1988</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Contains flyers, newsletters, and grant publications produced by the
			 office relating to public meetings, hearings, legislation, and current
			 activities.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<c02 level="file">
		  <did><container id="372e1277-e790-4d71-9598-437bfe3ff2b3" type="box">3</container><container parent="372e1277-e790-4d71-9598-437bfe3ff2b3" type="folder">1-2</container>
			 <unittitle>Publications. 
				<unitdate normal="1977/1988" type="inclusive">1977-1988</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		</c02>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="series">
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Series IV: Photographs, 
			 <unitdate normal="1986" type="inclusive">1986</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>One photograph of Priscillia Robinson in a working session with
			 members of the Water Quality Task Force; one of her at the signing of the
			 Environmental Quality Act of 1986, with Governor Babbitt and others; and one of
			 her with Dick Kamp and Bob Yuhnke standing beside an airplane.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<c02 level="file">
		  <did><container id="f6380b41-d873-4009-bf92-8a98f8eb4cb7" type="box">3</container><container parent="f6380b41-d873-4009-bf92-8a98f8eb4cb7" type="folder">3</container>
			 <unittitle>Photographs. 
				<unitdate normal="1986" type="inclusive">1986</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		</c02>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="series">
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Series V: Workshops and Projects, 
			 <unitdate normal="1975/1988" type="inclusive">1975-1988</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Contains correspondence, memos, reports, legal records, and printed
			 materials with federal, state, and independent agencies, environmental groups,
			 and members of Arizona's congressional delegation which documents SES
			 involvement and critique of standards, legislation, and reports on sundry
			 environmental issues and projects. Correspondents in the Smelter Advocacy
			 subseries include Sierra Club, Environmental Defense Fund, Smelter Crisis
			 Education Project (Naco, Arizona), Groups Against Smelter Pollution (Bisbee,
			 Arizona), Arizona Center for Law in the Public Interest, and congressional
			 representatives Morris Udall, Dennis DeConcini, James McNulty, John McCain, and
			 Jim Kolbe.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<c02 otherlevel="subsubseries">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>General</unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="67e52a80-9f61-4067-8051-8e5a27aa80f9" type="box">3</container><container parent="67e52a80-9f61-4067-8051-8e5a27aa80f9" type="folder">4-5</container>
				<unittitle>Catalina State Park: Correspondence. 
				  <unitdate normal="1975/1988" type="inclusive">1975-1988</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="9a58eb60-9015-4021-b7ad-0d7eba33d5e7" type="box">3</container><container parent="9a58eb60-9015-4021-b7ad-0d7eba33d5e7" type="folder">6-7</container>
				<unittitle>Catalina State Park: Printed materials. 
				  <unitdate normal="1975/1988" type="inclusive">1975-1988</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="ec846514-61d2-477d-8d15-8d440ed794d4" type="box">3</container><container parent="ec846514-61d2-477d-8d15-8d440ed794d4" type="folder">8</container>
				<unittitle>Tortolita Town Hall. 
				  <unitdate normal="1975" type="inclusive">1975</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="fbad7af6-8ea3-4a3b-9f91-fb4536b99cb6" type="box">3</container><container parent="fbad7af6-8ea3-4a3b-9f91-fb4536b99cb6" type="folder">9-10</container>
				<unittitle>Water Workshops: Correspondence and reports. 
				  <unitdate normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="61578d72-b5db-4892-b52b-7a6aac7ff257" type="box">3</container><container parent="61578d72-b5db-4892-b52b-7a6aac7ff257" type="folder">11</container>
				<unittitle>Gila River Water Quality Standards. 
				  <unitdate normal="1976/1982" type="inclusive">1976-1982</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="c90439a0-5ded-4c09-8602-d4c1c563be78" type="box">3</container><container parent="c90439a0-5ded-4c09-8602-d4c1c563be78" type="folder">12-13</container>
				<unittitle>Mount Lemon / Sabino Creek Water Quality:
				  Correspondence. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977/1985" type="inclusive">1977-1985</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="dfa719e7-1f82-4bf5-947c-bd2f64498414" type="box">3</container><container parent="dfa719e7-1f82-4bf5-947c-bd2f64498414" type="folder">14-16</container>
				<unittitle>Mount Lemon / Sabino Creek Water Quality: Lawsuit, USA
				  v. Pima County. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977/1985" type="inclusive">1977-1985</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="692eaacf-77b5-42b1-9264-332af96e85fa" type="box">4</container><container parent="692eaacf-77b5-42b1-9264-332af96e85fa" type="folder">1</container>
				<unittitle>Tortolita and Northwest Area Water Resources Study. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977" type="inclusive">1977</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="f91675d0-07a9-4f12-ad3e-6ff656bf5296" type="box">4</container><container parent="f91675d0-07a9-4f12-ad3e-6ff656bf5296" type="folder">2</container>
				<unittitle>Hydrologists Workshop. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977" type="inclusive">1977</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="afbe20b1-9ecf-4d0f-a07e-98ad350f954c" type="box">4</container><container parent="afbe20b1-9ecf-4d0f-a07e-98ad350f954c" type="folder">3</container>
				<unittitle>Water Quality: Regulations. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977/1986" type="inclusive">1977-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="5a26c2ec-5766-43a9-b62e-0403d50edbaf" type="box">4</container><container parent="5a26c2ec-5766-43a9-b62e-0403d50edbaf" type="folder">4</container>
				<unittitle>Water Quality: Legislation. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977/1986" type="inclusive">1977-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="f45191bc-10fd-43a6-a924-970e04555443" type="box">4</container><container parent="f45191bc-10fd-43a6-a924-970e04555443" type="folder">5-8</container>
				<unittitle>Water Quality: Revisions to Hawke bill. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977/1986" type="inclusive">1977-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="470e0955-b3f4-4263-b786-ad8e7b09dd8d" type="box">4</container><container parent="470e0955-b3f4-4263-b786-ad8e7b09dd8d" type="folder">9</container>
				<unittitle>Water Quality: Clippings, general. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977/1986" type="inclusive">1977-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="19cecb00-83b6-4be4-9af1-c2f3a81d5973" type="box">4</container><container parent="19cecb00-83b6-4be4-9af1-c2f3a81d5973" type="folder">10</container>
				<unittitle>Water Quality: Clippings, Environmental Quality Act. 
				  <unitdate normal="1977/1986" type="inclusive">1977-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="c0c08159-ef2f-4751-bb7e-201777a124f6" type="box">4</container><container parent="c0c08159-ef2f-4751-bb7e-201777a124f6" type="folder">11</container>
				<unittitle>Clean Air Workshop. 
				  <unitdate normal="1978" type="inclusive">1978</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="a55534df-bfa6-4f9f-853c-2ff30701c780" type="box">4</container><container parent="a55534df-bfa6-4f9f-853c-2ff30701c780" type="folder">12-13</container>
				<unittitle>Flood Hazards Education Project. 
				  <unitdate normal="1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="d5a3b07f-d0e9-44c9-8662-3554c284807c" type="box">4</container><container parent="d5a3b07f-d0e9-44c9-8662-3554c284807c" type="folder">14</container>
				<unittitle>Water Users Retreat. 
				  <unitdate normal="1982" type="inclusive">1982</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 otherlevel="subsubseries">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Smelter Advocacy</unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="ec1cf19a-cf04-4a92-a1bf-9ff5df42aa0a" type="box">4</container><container parent="ec1cf19a-cf04-4a92-a1bf-9ff5df42aa0a" type="folder">15</container>
				<unittitle>Multi-point rollback regulations. 
				  <unitdate normal="1979/1983" type="inclusive">1979-1983</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="8ae07ac9-f19e-4658-8c0b-979897434944" type="box">4</container><container parent="8ae07ac9-f19e-4658-8c0b-979897434944" type="folder">16</container>
				<unittitle>General: includes 1st Non-Ferrous Smelter Order (NSO)
				  regulations and hearings. 
				  <unitdate normal="1978/1979" type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="76a1d8b1-2d91-4eff-9e9e-8534305b3ca5" type="box">4</container><container parent="76a1d8b1-2d91-4eff-9e9e-8534305b3ca5" type="folder">17</container>
				<unittitle>General: includes U.S. Environmental Protection Service
				  hearing on visibility, Salt Lake City, Utah. 
				  <unitdate normal="1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="604cfd69-ed3d-404c-affe-223859e42b08" type="box">4</container><container parent="604cfd69-ed3d-404c-affe-223859e42b08" type="folder">18</container>
				<unittitle>General: includes Clean Air Act amendments and
				  congressional hearings. 
				  <unitdate normal="1981" type="inclusive">1981</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="c4ccf011-0bd1-435b-a889-3dcb1acbb1ad" type="box">5</container><container parent="c4ccf011-0bd1-435b-a889-3dcb1acbb1ad" type="folder">1-2</container>
				<unittitle>General: Clean Air Act amendments and acid rain. 
				  <unitdate normal="1981/1982" type="inclusive">1981-1982</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="b108a7f6-a4e9-4bf4-b755-7af28484ec32" type="box">5</container><container parent="b108a7f6-a4e9-4bf4-b755-7af28484ec32" type="folder">3-4</container>
				<unittitle>NSOs for Douglas and San Manuel, and Greenpeace caper. 
				  <unitdate normal="1982" type="inclusive">1982</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="50f23fbd-286f-4db8-b94b-fc0a03e85636" type="box">5</container><container parent="50f23fbd-286f-4db8-b94b-fc0a03e85636" type="folder">5-6</container>
				<unittitle>Loans to foreign copper companies and House Interior
				  committee hearings, Tucson, Arizona. 
				  <unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="01078d06-b967-478b-9537-a88a8669876a" type="box">5</container><container parent="01078d06-b967-478b-9537-a88a8669876a" type="folder">7</container>
				<unittitle>General: clippings. 
				  <unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="1fc8f469-4b88-4f1b-a823-f765e21f8099" type="box">5</container><container parent="1fc8f469-4b88-4f1b-a823-f765e21f8099" type="folder">8-10</container>
				<unittitle>Morenci and Douglas operating permits, western acid
				  rain, and smelters. 
				  <unitdate normal="1984" type="inclusive">1984</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="d3449d74-b5fd-4301-8935-048097641f44" type="box">5</container><container parent="d3449d74-b5fd-4301-8935-048097641f44" type="folder">11</container>
				<unittitle>Asarco compliance and cleanup. 
				  <unitdate normal="1981/1984" type="inclusive">1981-1984</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="ecfb9442-afa3-4f09-87e1-0738a924a5a6" type="box">5</container><container parent="ecfb9442-afa3-4f09-87e1-0738a924a5a6" type="folder">12-14</container>
				<unittitle>Grey Triangle agreements. 
				  <unitdate normal="1982/1987" type="inclusive">1982-1987</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="a4df5f78-cbbf-4c03-bd66-5dfdb217587b" type="box">5</container><container parent="a4df5f78-cbbf-4c03-bd66-5dfdb217587b" type="folder">15-16</container>
				<unittitle>Phelps Dodge union strikes: clippings. 
				  <unitdate normal="1983/1985" type="inclusive">1983-1985</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="3ab91be1-b61b-499e-8282-5a13454df9a8" type="box">6</container><container parent="3ab91be1-b61b-499e-8282-5a13454df9a8" type="folder">1</container>
				<unittitle>Lawsuit: Kamp vs. Hernandez, challenging the regulations
				  limiting the emission of sulfer dioxide from copper smelters in Arizona. 
				  <unitdate normal="1983/1985" type="inclusive">1983-1985</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="bf47b1a0-be7a-430f-8956-39c7ee105760" type="box">6</container><container parent="bf47b1a0-be7a-430f-8956-39c7ee105760" type="folder">2</container>
				<unittitle>Lawsuit: Environmental Defense Fund vs. Phelps Dodge and
				  Magma. 
				  <unitdate normal="1984/1986" type="inclusive">1984-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="b1bf2671-8db0-4eb0-ae7d-22ab9d0ab3ea" type="box">6</container><container parent="b1bf2671-8db0-4eb0-ae7d-22ab9d0ab3ea" type="folder">3</container>
				<unittitle>General: clippings. 
				  <unitdate normal="1985" type="inclusive">1985</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="d4f6c1c4-8f43-4d30-a419-1f948584910b" type="box">6</container><container parent="d4f6c1c4-8f43-4d30-a419-1f948584910b" type="folder">4-8</container>
				<unittitle>General: correspondence and reports: Acid rain, Douglas
				  smelter operating permit. 
				  <unitdate normal="1985" type="inclusive">1985</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="2bdbafc0-d800-472a-a7a6-d4877436a5db" type="box">6</container><container parent="2bdbafc0-d800-472a-a7a6-d4877436a5db" type="folder">9-11</container>
				<unittitle>General: clippings, Acid rain and Douglas smelter
				  operating permit. 
				  <unitdate normal="1985/1986" type="inclusive">1985-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="d7108161-2962-460c-9d01-c981ceabd5ef" type="box">6</container><container parent="d7108161-2962-460c-9d01-c981ceabd5ef" type="folder">12</container>
				<unittitle>Petition to EPA for SO2 standard to protect asthmatics. 
				  <unitdate normal="1985/1986" type="inclusive">1985-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="9986f0a4-086b-4649-ad76-cde96a8d7057" type="box">6</container><container parent="9986f0a4-086b-4649-ad76-cde96a8d7057" type="folder">13-15</container>
				<unittitle>Douglas smelter NSO, operating permit, temporary closure
				  and consent decree. 
				  <unitdate normal="1986" type="inclusive">1986</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container id="df39a7e3-0b1d-460c-89f9-1668e8c2f9b9" type="box">6</container><container parent="df39a7e3-0b1d-460c-89f9-1668e8c2f9b9" type="folder">16-19</container>
				<unittitle>Magma Copper Co. 2nd NSO and legal action, hearing
				  consent decree, and clippings. 
				  <unitdate normal="1983/1987" type="inclusive">1983-1987</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
	 </c01>
  </dsc> 
</archdesc></ead>