<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"> 
<eadheader audience="internal" findaidstatus="complete" langencoding="iso639-2b"> 
  <eadid encodinganalog="856$u">UAMS339</eadid> 
  <filedesc> 
	 <titlestmt> 
		<titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Broadsides from Mexico Collection, 
		  <date>1676-1927, bulk 1820-1927</date></titleproper> 
		<author encodinganalog="245$c">Inventory prepared by Theresa A. Strottman
		  and Natalia Kaczkurkin.</author> 
	 </titlestmt> 
	 <publicationstmt> 
		<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special
		  Collections</publisher> 
		<address> 
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline> 
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
</address> 
		<date>2006</date> 
		<p>Arizona Board of Regents. All Rights Reserved.</p> 
	 </publicationstmt> 
  </filedesc> 
  <profiledesc> 
	 <creation encodinganalog="500">Inventory encoded by Peggy Cabrera. 
		<date>July 2004</date></creation> 
	 <langusage>Inventory is in<language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">
		English.</language></langusage> 
  </profiledesc> 
<revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-06-21">2017-06-21</date><item>This finding aid was updated in alignment with LC EAD 2.0 specifications using a python script created by Erik Radio.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader> 
<frontmatter> 
  <titlepage> 
	 <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Broadsides from Mexico Collection, 
		<date>1676-1927, bulk 1820-1927</date></titleproper> 
	 <num>Collection Number: MS 339</num> 
	 <publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special
		Collections</publisher> 
	 <list> 
		<defitem> 
		  <label>Processed by:</label> 
		  <item>Theresa A. Strottman and Natalia Kaczkurkin</item> 
		</defitem> 
		<defitem> 
		  <label>Date completed:</label> 
		  <item> 
			 <date>August 2000</date></item> 
		</defitem> 
		<defitem> 
		  <label>Encoded by:</label> 
		  <item>Peggy Cabrera</item> 
		</defitem> 
	 </list> 
	 <p>© 2006. Arizona Board of Regents. All rights reserved.</p> 
  </titlepage> 
</frontmatter> 
<archdesc encodinganalog="351$c" level="collection"> 
  <did> 
	 <head>Collection Summary</head> 
	 <unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Collection Name">Broadsides from
		Mexico Collection, 
		<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">1676-1927, bulk
		  1820-1927</unitdate></unittitle> 
	 <unitid countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099" label="Collection Number" repositorycode="US-azu">MS 339</unitid> 
	 <origination label="Provenance">This collection does not have any specific
		purchase or accession records in Special Collections which indicate its
		provenance. It was purchased in the 1970s from the Texas based Serendipity Co.
		The Lilly Library in Bloomington, Indiana sold these broadsides via Serendipity
		Co. because they were duplicates. There is a folder containing a control file
		documenting the provenance of a small number of related materials which have
		been incorporated into this collection</origination>
	 <abstract label="Abstract">This collection contains approximately 2,000
		Mexican broadsides, publicly distributed documents, issued by various offices
		of the federal, state, municipal, and local governments during the 19th and
		early 20th centuries. Apart from a few broadsides in French in the Zacatecas (5
		of 5) folder, all the broadsides are in Spanish</abstract> 
	 <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Physical Description"><extent encodinganalog="300">8 linear feet</extent></physdesc> 
	 <repository label="Repository"> 
		<corpname encodinganalog="110">University of Arizona Libraries, Special
		  Collections</corpname> 
		<address> 
		  <addressline>University of Arizona</addressline> 
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline> 
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
</address></repository> 
  </did> 
  <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506"> 
	 <head>Restrictions</head> 
	 <p>None.</p> 
  </accessrestrict> 
  <userestrict encodinganalog="540"> 
	 <head>Copyright</head> 
	 <p>It is the responsibility of the user to obtain permission to publish
		from the owner of the copyright (the institution, the creator of the record,
		the author or his/her transferees, heirs, legates, or literary executors). The
		user agrees to indemnify and hold harmless the Arizona Board of Regents for the
		University of Arizona, its officers, employees, and agents from and against all
		claims made by any person asserting that he or she is an owner of
		copyright.</p> 
  </userestrict> 
  <prefercite encodinganalog="524"> 
	 <head>Credit Line</head> 
	 <p>Broadsides from Mexico Collection (MS 339). Special
		Collections, University of Arizona Libraries.</p> 
  </prefercite> 
  <arrangement> 
	 <head>Organization</head> 
	 <p>This collection is organized into two series:</p> 
	 <list> 
		<item>Series I. State Broadsides, 
		  <unitdate normal="1820/1927" type="inclusive">1820-1927</unitdate></item> 
	 </list> 
	 <list> 
		<item>Series II. Federal Government Broadsides, 
		  <unitdate normal="1676/1910" type="inclusive">1676-1910</unitdate></item> 
	 </list> 
  </arrangement> 
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="520"> 
	 <head>Scope and Content Note</head> 
	 <p>Topics referred to in these broadsides include invasions by Spain,
		France and the United States of America; mobilization for wars, including the
		Mexican American War; soldiers; elections; government positions; decretos
		(decrees); courts; prisoners; and financial issues, such as taxes, budgets, and
		customs. Often the broadsides in the individual state folders contain
		information from the federal government which the governor of the state
		released and signed. Some documents refer to the political conflicts between
		those who supported the Roman Catholic Church and those who advocated rigorous
		anti-clericalism. Also included are specific Plans, a 19th century aspect of
		Mexican political culture whereby a military or political leader would publish
		a Plan, usually named after where it was issued, and wait to see how many other
		political and military leaders would support it.</p> 
  </scopecontent> 
  <controlaccess> 
	 <persname>Santa Anna, Antonio López de, --
			 1794?-1876</persname><persname>Bustamante, Anastasio, --
			 1780-1853</persname><persname>Alamillo, J. Trinidad, --
			 1857-1937</persname><persname>Juárez, Benito, --
			 1806-1872</persname><persname>Gomez, Gilardo</persname><persname>Betancourt, Alberto</persname><persname>Iturbide, Agustín de, --
			 1783-1824</persname><corpname>Catholic Church -- Mexico --
			 History</corpname><subject>Religion and politics -- Mexico</subject><subject>Church and state -- Mexico -- History</subject><subject>Printing -- Mexico</subject><subject>Politics and culture -- Mexico</subject><subject>Broadsides -- Mexico</subject><subject>Elections -- Mexico -- History</subject><subject>Mexican War, 1846-1848</subject><geogname>Mexico -- Church history</geogname><geogname>Mexico -- History -- French Invasion, 1838-1839</geogname><geogname>Mexico -- Politics and government -- 1540-1810</geogname><geogname>Mexico -- Politics and government -- 1821-1861</geogname><geogname>Mexico -- Politics and government -- 1861-1867</geogname><geogname>Mexico -- Politics and government -- 1867-1910</geogname><geogname>Mexico -- Politics and government -- 1910-1946</geogname><geogname>Mexico -- History -- Spanish Invasion, 1829</geogname></controlaccess> 
  <dsc type="combined"> 
	 <head>Container List</head> 
	 <c01 level="series"> 
		<did> 
		  <unittitle>Series I: State Broadsides, 
			 <unitdate normal="1820/1927" type="inclusive">1820-1927</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="a6b1688a-e582-43e5-85e4-f01481d6d1a3" type="box">1</container> <container parent="a6b1688a-e582-43e5-85e4-f01481d6d1a3" type="folder">1</container> 
			 <unittitle>Aguascalientes, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">August 26, 1829 - October 19,
				  1852</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are mobilization for wars, including the
				Mexican American War, soldiers, anti-clericalism, taxes, lists of jurors, and
				declarations of civil holidays at Christmas.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Felipe Cosio and Augustín
				Domingues.</p> 
			 <p>Two oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="7eafdcb4-1633-4a26-a2c8-1caebddcadd7" type="box">1</container> <container parent="7eafdcb4-1633-4a26-a2c8-1caebddcadd7" type="folder">2</container> 
			 <unittitle>Baja California, 
				<unitdate normal="1911" type="inclusive">April 22,
				  1911</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="0f2e801e-6824-4bfd-9cf9-88c939e94594" type="box">1</container> <container parent="0f2e801e-6824-4bfd-9cf9-88c939e94594" type="folder">3</container> 
			 <unittitle>Chiapas, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">August 1, 1829 - June 10,
				  1849</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are congressional fear of a Spanish invasion
				in 1829, government positions, the governor's speech opening a congressional
				session, and decretos (decrees) concerning securing property and financing for
				construction of a Palacio de los Supremos Poderes and a military parade
				ground.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Ignacio Barberena.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="347f3aa9-8223-471a-8fd3-57cf3d9a21b0" type="box">1</container> <container parent="347f3aa9-8223-471a-8fd3-57cf3d9a21b0" type="folder">4</container> 
			 <unittitle>Chihuahua, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">March 6, 1829 - May 26,
				  1910</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are congressional sessions, support of
				federal form of government for the nation, Roman Catholicism as the only state
				sanctioned religion, border disputes and alliances with Durango, judicial
				procedures, rebellion in various areas of Mexico including what is now New
				Mexico (1837), defeat of Texan invaders by soldiers from Santa Fe (1841),
				mobilization for wars, including the Mexican American War, soldiers, elections,
				taxes, government officials, and a 1910 contract signed by Porfirio Díaz
				deeding a small gold and silver mine to an American owned company. Plans
				mentioned include the Plan de Cuernavaca (1834) and the Plan de Jalapa
				(1850).</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include José Antonio Arce,
				José Isidro Madero, José S. Pareja, Albino Perez, José
				Gonzales, Manuel Armijo, José Mariano Monteverde, Ignacio Ocadiz,
				Estevan Aguirre, and Porfirio Díaz.</p> 
			 <p>One oversize item is located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="e483f8c7-5a26-47c2-bd4f-3372b6c42f76" type="box">1</container> <container parent="e483f8c7-5a26-47c2-bd4f-3372b6c42f76" type="folder">5</container> 
			 <unittitle>Coahuila, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">October 17, 1829 - September
				  6, 1927</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are decretos (decrees), state finances,
				government positions and appointments, taxes, budgets, elections, legislative
				pardons for prisoners, commutations of death sentences, a border conflict with
				Durango, cultivation of tobacco, and health and building codes. There are also
				permits to build electricity plants, telephone service, telegraph lines, and
				factories for producing various goods such as beer. There are no documents from
				the period of the Mexican American War.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Francisco Mejía, Miguel
				Cárdenas, Venustiano Carranza, Evaristo Madero, Hipólito Charles,
				Jesus de Valle, and Jesus Valdés Mejía.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="5b45e1e8-1512-4096-872d-35b2db690276" type="box">1</container> <container parent="5b45e1e8-1512-4096-872d-35b2db690276" type="folder">6</container> 
			 <unittitle>Colima (1 of 3), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">July 10, 1829 - December 16,
				  1889</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are decretos (decrees), contracts and
				announcements. Some topics referred to in these broadsides are government
				positions, state finances, taxes, budgets, elections, setting coach fares, land
				management, railroad construction, care of prisoners and syphilitic women,
				regulations against graffiti, monetary reform, tramway construction, thatch
				fences, regulations for pharmacies, weavers workshops, and slaughterhouses,
				education, and support of local students studying in other states. There is a
				fifty-nine year gap between the first document which refers to an anticipated
				Spanish invasion in 1829 and the rest of the broadsides which were issued in
				1888 and 1889. </p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Gilardo Gómez and Alberto
				Betancourt and J. Trinidad Alamillo.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="89c62c87-5bb1-4237-a6c6-8f6c99718444" type="box">1</container> <container parent="89c62c87-5bb1-4237-a6c6-8f6c99718444" type="folder">7</container> 
			 <unittitle>Colima (2 of 3), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">March 16, 1890 - December 16,
				  1891</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are decretos (decrees), contracts, government
				positions, elections, taxes, state finances, monetary reform, pardons of prison
				sentences, imposition of the maximum sentence, education standards, support of
				local students studying in other states, standard weights and measures,
				business regulations, restriction of the hours during which bells could be rung
				in the capital, establishment of an orphanage, regulations regarding visible
				address tiles on residences, regulations against graffiti, regulation
				prohibiting people, horses and cattle from crossing railroad tracks,
				slaughterhouse regulations, contracts for electric lighting and tram
				construction, and permits to build factories for producing various goods such
				as ice.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Gilardo Gómez, Alberto
				Betancourt, and J. Trinidad Alamillo.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="ab5cae02-2edf-4ef1-9102-487b268febd8" type="box">2</container> <container parent="ab5cae02-2edf-4ef1-9102-487b268febd8" type="folder">1</container> 
			 <unittitle>Colima (3 of 3), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 14, 1892 - August 8,
				  1894</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are decretos (decrees), contracts, government
				positions, elections, taxes on coffee production, livestock and harvests, state
				finances, budgets, regulation prohibiting horsemen, carriages and cattle from
				crossing railroad tracks, registration of births, time limits for settling
				estates, definitions of injury, calumny, and defamation, fuel for public
				electric lighting, water shortages, pardon of the death penalty but commuted to
				maximum prison term, professional certification, education, widows and orphans,
				licenses for beggars, prohibitions against carrying arms, and regulations for
				slaughterhouses, coach fares, domestic servants, scribes and notaries.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include J. Trinidad Alamillo, Gilardo
				Gómez, Alberto Betancourt, Miguel Alvarez, Remigio Rodríguez, and
				Francisco Santa Cruz.</p> 
			 <p>One oversize item is located in Oversize Flat File .</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="9fbbf451-5646-4f3a-aabc-33bbf0d944bb" type="box">2</container> <container parent="9fbbf451-5646-4f3a-aabc-33bbf0d944bb" type="folder">2</container> 
			 <unittitle>Durango, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">August 27, 1828 - May 15,
				  1844</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, criticisms and
				pleas from municipalities to the state government, state support for the Plan
				of Jalapa, state transfer of 30,000 pesos to the federal government, civilian
				militia, two senators appointed to manage state government when the state
				legislature was dissolved during a revolution in 1832, need for police in
				Durango when it became the state capital in 1844, and the new governor's letter
				to the citizens</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Francisco Elorriaga, José
				Ignacio Gutierrez, and José A. Heredia. </p> 
			 <p>Eight oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="282c5da0-76e3-40e4-b14f-3ba3e439f2e4" type="box">2</container> <container parent="282c5da0-76e3-40e4-b14f-3ba3e439f2e4" type="folder">3</container> 
			 <unittitle>Guanajuato, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">December 22, 1828 - May 7,
				  1847</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, expulsion of
				Spaniards from Mexico, the 1829 invasion by Spain, declaration of the end of
				the national emergency and a call for reestablishment of civil order,
				evacuation of Spaniards, coalition with Jalisco, Queretaro, Zacatecas, San Luis
				Potosi, Michoacan and Durango, blockade of Mexico by France, 1838 war with
				France, state request to the federal government asking punishment for those who
				support Mexico adopting a monarchical form of government, call for the end of
				the despotic administration of Antonio Lopez de Santa Anna, fund to aid those
				wounded defending the Constitution, list of citizens qualified to be elected to
				Congress, state payments to the federal government to help finance the war with
				Texas, declaration nullifying the 1846 elections, and economic measures during
				the Mexican American War. </p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Juan Morales, Antonio López
				de Santa Anna, and Lorenzo Arellano.</p> 
			 <p>Seven oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="c1b3c0e5-0819-4e2c-a80e-e568bc5f6bcd" type="box">2</container> <container parent="c1b3c0e5-0819-4e2c-a80e-e568bc5f6bcd" type="folder">4</container> 
			 <unittitle>Guerrero, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">March 16, 1910 - July 28,
				  1910</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are decretos (decrees), reform of the penal
				code, fines assessed in courts, taxes, and the tax on the slaughter of
				cattle.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Silvano Saavedra, Damian Flores.</p>
			 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="5768a505-61f0-487a-9911-0f5b74b5ee90" type="box">2</container> <container parent="5768a505-61f0-487a-9911-0f5b74b5ee90" type="folder">5</container> 
			 <unittitle>Jalisco, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">September 18, 1820 - August
				  19, 1855</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are the Comandante General de Nueva Galicia
				freeing all French except criminals, independence, free establishment of
				factories, elimination of titles, certifications and union memberships as
				requirements for working at any profession, prohibiting cavalry escorts to all
				ranks below capitanes generales, the Roman Catholic Church, anticlericalism,
				civil versus clerical rights and monies, the Spanish Cortes, elections, support
				for the federal form of government, laws for Guadalajara, 1828 Spanish
				invasion, government positions, prisoners to work mines, Plan de Zavaleta,
				constitutional reform, ports for the Pacific trade, 1838 French invasion,
				tobacco monopoly, Plan de Cuernavaca, the Mexican American War, and monetary
				reform. Plans mentioned include the Plan de Cuernavaca .</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include José de la Cruz,
				Augustín Iturbide, Vicente Guerrero, José Ignacio Cañedo,
				Rafael Sanchez, Antonio López de Santa Anna and Joaquín
				Angulo.</p> 
			 <p>Fifty-five oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="f41552ee-6edf-4899-a170-71b99955e467" type="box">2</container> <container parent="f41552ee-6edf-4899-a170-71b99955e467" type="folder">6</container> 
			 <unittitle>Mexico, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">April 5, 1823 - November 28,
				  1911</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are recognizing Iturbide as emperor defined
				as treason, elections, courts, gauchupinesco, 1829 Spanish invasion, finances,
				budgets, taxes, government loans, customs, ports, government positions, army,
				support of the Catholic Church, anticlericalism, exile, asylum, honorific
				orders and decorations, support for widows of soldiers, 1838 French invasion,
				veterans, counterfeit money, Tacubaya, protecting Mexican industry from cheaper
				imports, factory seals to identify their products, amnesty for political
				prisoners, destruction of a building by soldiers and prisoners to build a
				plaza, caudillismo, Mexican American War, the coalition formed by the states of
				Aguascalientes, Jaliso, Michoacan, Querétaro, San Luis Potosí and
				Zacatecas, and recess of the state congress. Plans mentioned include the Plan
				de San Luis Potosí.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Augustín Iturbide,
				José Mariano Marin, Francisco Molinos del Campo, Lorenzo de Zavala,
				Anastasio Bustamante, José María Esquivel, José
				María Rozas, Mariano Buen Abad, Luis Gonzaga Vieyra, Antonio
				López de Santa Anna, Nicolás Bravo, Valentín Canalizo,
				Manuel Rincon, José Joaquín de Herrera, Mucio Barquera and
				Mariano Paredes y Arrillaga.</p> 
			 <p>Twenty-seven oversize items located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="c700dc4c-a779-428a-95c6-ba92378e55fa" type="box">2</container> <container parent="c700dc4c-a779-428a-95c6-ba92378e55fa" type="folder">7</container> 
			 <unittitle>Michoacán, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">December 20, 1828 - July 3,
				  1848</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="b3777db0-4d11-405c-87e7-0be34b2e76e9" type="box">2</container> <container parent="b3777db0-4d11-405c-87e7-0be34b2e76e9" type="folder">8</container> 
			 <unittitle>Morelos, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 5, 1910 - December 17,
				  1910</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, public works
				department for the state, leave of absence for the governor, finances, taxes,
				alcohol, sugar, funding for medicine, meals and employees for seven state
				hospitals, schools, tax exemption for Roman Catholic Church justified by its
				good works and provision of free public education, taxation and regulation of
				the cattle industry, fees for rides in coaches, permission from federal
				government to import rifles and ammunition, and elections.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Pablo Escandon and Augustín
				Hurtado de Mendoza.</p> 
			 <p>Two oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="a53da65d-e5c5-43d6-b80e-4f59f6963825" type="box">2</container> <container parent="a53da65d-e5c5-43d6-b80e-4f59f6963825" type="folder">9</container> 
			 <unittitle>Nuevo León, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 28, 1828 - April 5,
				  1852</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, lists of jurors,
				lists of voters, Roman Catholic Church, anticlericalism, state appropriation of
				Roman Catholic Church properties, public order restored by the garrison,
				submission of state governments to the federal government, support of Roman
				Catholic Church, military alliance with surrounding states, 1836 negotiations
				to release Santa Anna who was captured by Texans, 1838 break of diplomatic
				relations between France and Mexico, national foreign debt, revolution, support
				Plan de Jalisco, control Indian tribes on the frontier, Plan de San Luis
				Potosi, taxes, finances, Mexican American War, call to arms, draft all males
				between the ages of eighteen and fifty, and support of the federal government.
				</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Manuel Mariano de Llano, José
				Rafael de la Garza, Gregorio Zambrano, Antonio López de Santa Anna, Juan
				Bautista de Arizpe, Juan Nepomuceno de la Garza y Evia, Mariano Paredes y
				Arrillaga, José María de Ortega, and Jesus Garza Gonzales.</p> 
			 <p>Two oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="531393bc-bb7e-4f46-a72e-475bc55404d2" type="box">2</container> <container parent="531393bc-bb7e-4f46-a72e-475bc55404d2" type="folder">10</container> 
			 <unittitle>Oaxaca, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 4, 1828 - April 28,
				  1838</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are the opening statement of the Second
				Constitutional Congress expressing confidence in the rule of law after a period
				of turmoil, army, garrison, and the 1838 break of diplomatic relations between
				France and Mexico.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Francisco Monterrubio and
				José López de Ortigosa.</p> 
			 <p>One oversize items is located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="50b240b4-2fb7-437f-84fd-a89dfa7cd22f" type="box">2</container> <container parent="50b240b4-2fb7-437f-84fd-a89dfa7cd22f" type="folder">11</container> 
			 <unittitle>Puebla, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">April 28, 1821 - December 25,
				  1867</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, Plan de Iturbide,
				alliance with Oaxaca and Veracruz, end civil obligation to tithe, licenses for
				arms, army, garrison, elections, call to arms, 1838 French invasion, penalties
				for theft, roads, ports, cotton, Mexican American War, moving the seat of
				government, customs, state debt, cacao, taxes, judicial districts, anarchists,
				vagrants, restrict hours for ringing Church bells, Cinco de Mayo
				commemorations, education, mental hospital, state seals on documents,
				elections, squatters, war debt, fines, institution for deaf and dumb children,
				adult education, tax on imported flour, decretos (decrees), and abolition of
				road tolls. </p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Juan Mendoz, Augustín de
				Iturbide, Anastasio Bustamante, Juan Mugica y Osorio, Antonio López de
				Santa Anna, Patricio Fúrlong, Cosme Fúrlong, Rafael J.
				García, Cayetano María Perez de Leon, Manuel Rincon, Domingo
				Ybarra, Nicolás Bravo, Miguel C. de Alatriste, Benito Juárez and
				José de la Luz Palafox.</p> 
			 <p>Twenty-five oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="6a194c64-8427-46ca-9ad1-779211ff5934" type="box">3</container> <container parent="6a194c64-8427-46ca-9ad1-779211ff5934" type="folder">1</container> 
			 <unittitle>Querétaro, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">February 14, 1829 - June 30,
				  1911</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, expulsion of
				Spaniards, revolt in Yucatan, Congress, military revolt in Jalapa, coalition
				with Durango, Guanajuato, Jalisco, Michoacan, San Luis Potosi, and Zacatecas,
				state funeral, courts, judges, support of federal government, Mexican American
				War, Battle of Cerro Gordo, protecting Mexican industry from cheaper imports,
				Roman Catholic Church, Mass, processions, 1838 French blockade, elections and
				state revenues.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include José Rafael Canalizo, Lino
				Ramirez, and Miguel López de Ecala.</p> 
			 <p>Seven oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="f7b37b75-9e1e-4215-8b13-9b2495d02f0c" type="box">3</container> <container parent="f7b37b75-9e1e-4215-8b13-9b2495d02f0c" type="folder">2</container> 
			 <unittitle>San Luis Potosí (1 of 2), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">November 25, 1826 - Nov. 28,
				  1848</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, Spanish battle with
				Mexican forces under Santa Anna at Tampico in 1829, elections, Spanish
				conspirators, expulsion of Spaniards, support for the federal government,
				support for soldiers who fought the Spanish, salaries for government positions,
				robbery of a Roman Catholic Church, Plan de Jalapa, jurors, finances, taxes,
				alcabalas, excise taxes, state loans, judges, land sales by the government,
				soldiers, Mexican American War, ports, export duties, state funeral, tax relief
				for poor earning under 100 pesos per year, money, survey of prefecturas, arming
				rural ranches and haciendas, revolts in the mountains, tobacco, sentences for
				crimes, roads, Roman Catholic Church, wills, lumber imports, army, and the
				Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Julian de los Reyes, Antonio
				López de Santa Anna, Vicente Romero, Luis de Cortazar, Manuel Sanchez,
				José Maria Rincon Gallardo, José Maria Flores, Mariano Martinez,
				Matilde Ordáz, Juan José Zenon Fernandez, Manuel Gomez Pedrosa,
				Anastasio Bustamante, Juan Valentín Amador, Ramon Adame, and José
				María Otahegui.</p> 
			 <p>Ten oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File. </p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="fb039023-ebda-41ae-bb4f-28bb8040b505" type="box">3</container> <container parent="fb039023-ebda-41ae-bb4f-28bb8040b505" type="folder">3</container> 
			 <unittitle>San Luis Potosí (2 of 2), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">April 24, 1850 - Nov. 29,
				  1861</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, elections, state
				appointment of bishops, soldiers, army, constitutional reform, Masses said for
				Iturbide and the army, congressional agenda, Baja California, support for the
				horses of army personnel, health of army personnel, Indian tribes, judges,
				courts, legislators, senate, governor, anarchy, finances, budgets, taxes,
				loans, state and federal debts, levy of mounted men to maintain safety on the
				roads, amnesty for revolutionaries, tierras baldias colonizable by
				corporations, counterfeit money, professional certification, customs, ports,
				defense of the Isthmus of Tehuantepec, Mexican American War, local wines and
				aguardientes, defense of Matamoros, monopoly for playing cards, salaries,
				public granary, grain, ranches and haciendas, civil unrest, La Reforma,
				alliance with Zacatecas, Aguascalientes, Guanajuato, Morelia, and Tamaulipas,
				compensation for property ruined during the war for La Reforma, martial law,
				honorific titles, levies, exile of reactionary soldiers, federal constitution,
				pardon for all sentenced to corporal punishment except murderers,
				revolutionaries, and a proclamation denying state recognition of foreign
				authorities. </p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Julian de los Reyes, José
				Joaquín Herrera, Miguel Laso, José Guadalupe de los Reyes,
				Mariano Arista, Manuel Díaz de la Vega, Vicente Chico Sein, Benito
				Juárez, Francisco P. Villanueva and Sóstenes Escandon.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="451ae70e-912a-48ad-9696-b00d32b30efd" type="box">3</container> <container parent="451ae70e-912a-48ad-9696-b00d32b30efd" type="folder">4</container> 
			 <unittitle>Sinaloa, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">October 31, 1833 - November
				  29, 1846</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are government positions, the Mexican
				American War, call to arms, and call for unity.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Carlos Espinosa de los Monteros.</p>
			 
			 <p>Three oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="605c9cbc-2033-4881-a553-b17b0375066a" type="box">3</container> <container parent="605c9cbc-2033-4881-a553-b17b0375066a" type="folder">5</container> 
			 <unittitle>Sonora, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">February 25, 1832 - May 21,
				  1846</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are ports, state congress' rejection of
				federal congress' proposed constitutional reforms which limited states rights,
				and the Mexican American War.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Antonio López de Santa Anna,
				José Ramon Terrazas, Manuel Escalante y Mason, and Juan Bautista
				Gandara.</p> 
			 <p>One oversize item is located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="9d6d13a4-e999-4c96-bfc6-e301c227d557" type="box">3</container> <container parent="9d6d13a4-e999-4c96-bfc6-e301c227d557" type="folder">6</container> 
			 <unittitle>Tamaulipas, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">November 20, 1829 - June 30,
				  1887</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are 1828 Spanish invasion, support of the
				federal system of government, state legislature's dismissal of the governor,
				elections, and municipal government regulations.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include José Antonio Fernandez and
				Gregorio de Leon.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="20b0bd37-c598-4ee0-ac62-3fc14e6d37bb" type="box">3</container> <container parent="20b0bd37-c598-4ee0-ac62-3fc14e6d37bb" type="folder">7</container> 
			 <unittitle>Tlaxcala, 
				<unitdate normal="NaN/1829" type="inclusive">September 21, 1828 -
				  1829</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are the 1829 Spanish invasion and
				soldiers.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include José Antonio de
				Saldaña and Cristóbal Gonzalez Angulo.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="de15d75f-0770-4cde-be2c-77051967469f" type="box">3</container> <container parent="de15d75f-0770-4cde-be2c-77051967469f" type="folder">8</container> 
			 <unittitle>Veracruz, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">May 30, 1820 - February 1,
				  1834</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are elections, aid for the widows of those
				killed during the 1828 Spanish invasion, and congress.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include José Davila Davila, Antonio
				Juille y Moreno, Antonio López de Santa Anna and Leonardo Romay.</p> 
			 <p>Two oversize items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="089b275c-ed3d-4163-bce6-b4d1c20b3e58" type="box">3</container> <container parent="089b275c-ed3d-4163-bce6-b4d1c20b3e58" type="folder">9</container> 
			 <unittitle>Yucatán, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 4, 1834 - January 2,
				  1846</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are the state army, jurors, and
				Yucatán's refusal to recognize the federal government because it broke
				the pact which tied Yucátan to the rest of the republic.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Francisco Martinez de Arredondo,
				José Tiburcio López, and Miguel Barbachano.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="4a162a44-23ab-4503-bd65-560945f3c00e" type="box">3</container> <container parent="4a162a44-23ab-4503-bd65-560945f3c00e" type="folder">10</container> 
			 <unittitle>Zacatecas (1 of 5), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">July 1, 1824 - December 14,
				  1850</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are constitutions, laws, decretos (decrees),
				government positions, finances, taxes, tobacco, alcohol, legitimacy, Roman
				Catholic Church, clergy, cattle, civil militia, loans from the state to the
				federal government, draft, juntas patrioticas, army, soldiers, judges,
				certification of doctors, Spanish colonial rule, independence, elections,
				anticlericalism, suspension of the federal government's religious reforms which
				were rejected by most of the nation to maintain peace, threatened invasion by
				Durango, 1836 war with Texas, pardons for Texan prisoners, changes in the
				departamento status of Texas, New Mexico, California, Coahuila, Colima, and
				Tlaxcala, French blockade, customs, ports, aid from the state to pueblos during
				epidemics, mints, copper, contraband, and Tacubaya.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Pedro José Lopez de Nava,
				Francisco Garcia, Vicente Guerro, Mariano del Castillo, José A. Heredia,
				Manuel G. Cosio, Santiago Villegas, Fernando Franco, and Antonio López
				de Santa Anna.</p> 
			 <p>One hundred forty-three oversize items are located in Oversize
				Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="5bce7eca-b3d0-4fbe-a8b4-da6bd21d2e7f" type="box">4</container> <container parent="5bce7eca-b3d0-4fbe-a8b4-da6bd21d2e7f" type="folder">1</container> 
			 <unittitle>Zacatecas (2 of 5), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 3, 1851 - December 10,
				  1853</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are customs, ports, tobacco, Tacubaya,
				regulation of sulfuric acid, mail rates for newspapers, taxes on the slaughter
				of cattle, congress, decretos, finances, debt, ships, Spaniards with Mexican
				citizenship, judges, courts, Roman Catholic Church, manos muertos, army, Texas,
				fines and fees, prisons, government positions, ayuntamientos, juntas
				municipales, pensions for veterans wives and children, draft, alliance with
				Chihuahua and Durango, commission to negotiate the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo,
				identity documents, public education, schools, elections, retired military
				personnel, marriages, regulation of printing presses, support for the state
				government of San Luis Potosi battling rebels, cholera epidemic, public health
				care funding, alcohol taxes, state funeral, judges, constitutional reform, ban
				on the sale of certain foods, holidays, anticlericalism, subsidies for feeding
				cavalry horses, war on the frontiers with Indian tribes, salaries for
				government positions, per diem, travel expenses, prisoners, cartographic and
				statistical study of the state, expropriation of salt lands and waters,
				regulations for religious processions, Holy Week, payments by the state to the
				federal government, Mexican made fabrics exempt from taxes, convicts
				subcontracted from the state to mine owners to work the mines, state granting a
				villa the right to hold a ten day fair in late January every year for five
				years, fees for grazing animals in private fields bordering roads, national
				guard registration, and counterfeit money. </p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Antonio López de Santa Anna,
				Fernando Franco, Marcos de Esparza, José Mariano de Salas, Casiano
				Gonzalez Veyna, Manuel Gonzalez Cosio, Antonio Garza, José
				Joaquín de Herrera, José Gonzalez y Echeverria and Mariano
				Arista.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="0ef3433d-2d21-4eac-a171-64bcec4f5c4d" type="box">4</container> <container parent="0ef3433d-2d21-4eac-a171-64bcec4f5c4d" type="folder">2</container> 
			 <unittitle>Zacatecas (3 of 5), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 14, 1854 - December
				  24, 1856</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are education, salaries for teachers,
				assayers, decretos, Indian tribes, bandits, Roman Catholic Church,
				anticlericalism, elections Isthmus de Tehuantepec, regulations for religious
				processions, customs, ports, Plan de Guadalajara, thieves to be judged by
				military courts, cavalry, national guard, government positions, army,
				observances for Santa Anna's birthday, finances, budgets, taxes, courts,
				judges, explosives, mines, appropriation of private buildings for military
				barracks, hospitals, etc., road construction, rebels, commercial licenses for
				alcohol, tax on mules and burros for road maintenance, valid military
				decorations, exile of Carbajal, dress code, state seals on diplomas, limit
				political rights of tenants, affirm private property to salt lands and waters,
				president of the republic assumption of the states' right to appoint clergy,
				tithe no longer a civil obligation, mourning for federal minister, tobacco,
				reestablishment of the Jesuits, military pardon for deserters, pensions,
				monetary reform, security cards for foreign residents, paper made in Mexico,
				military draft, regulations defining the nationality of companies with foreign
				investors, censorship of books including imported books, vagrants, regulations
				for the border with Texas, federal government assumes the title for tierras
				baldias, monetary regulations, counterfeit money, mandatory arms in areas with
				Indian tribes, commercial code, regulations for lighting all public, religious
				and educational buildings during the evening hours of public celebrations,
				paint houses one of four approved colors, Plan de Ayutla, prohibition of
				fireworks, freedom of the press, slaughter of cattle, mail, mandatory public
				education, soldiers, three months pardon for convicts, and exports of gold and
				silver. </p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include José Gonzalez y Echeverria,
				Mariano Arista, Antonio López de Santa Anna, Ventura Mora, Manuel
				Gonzalez, Francisco G. Pavón, Manuel Zavala, Fernando A. Velasco,
				Victoriano Zamora, Juan Alvarez, and Ignacio Comonfort.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="1ed7af3e-7ce4-47ca-96da-c757585cfa92" type="box">4</container> <container parent="1ed7af3e-7ce4-47ca-96da-c757585cfa92" type="folder">3</container> 
			 <unittitle>Zacatecas (4 of 5), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 1, 1857 - May 20,
				  1862</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are compensation for those lands Santa Anna
				expropriated, thieves, government positions, reversal of reestablishment of the
				Jesuits, criminal sentences, negate military honors given by Santa Anna from
				1853 to 1855, recognize military honors of those who fought in Guaymas in 1854,
				finances, budgets, taxes, tobacco, military deserters, permission to marry from
				bosses or officers necessary for government and military personnel, Plan de
				Ayutla, courts, judges, bandits, Indian tribes, silver exports, customs, ports,
				elections, regulations for religious processions, eliminate veterans privileges
				and salaries, national guard, curfew and martial law, cancellation of railroad
				contract, pardon for convicts with only two months of their sentences
				remaining, establishment of a lottery to pay the national debt to New York
				bankers, salt lands income dedicated to education, closing congress until order
				reestablished, Constitution of 1857, La Reforma, suspension of privileges
				granted mining corporations, Roman Catholic Church, anticlericalism,
				confiscation of convents, nationalization of Church wealth, bandits, exile
				opposition, disarm public, Independence Day and other public holidays,
				principle of equality, amnesty for political crimes, decretos, minors under
				twenty-one need their parents permission to marry, Battle of Azogueros,
				opposition forces of S. Ramirez, money, sale of Roman Catholic Church property,
				sanitation, elections, army, frontier ports, secularize hospitals, laws
				protecting peons, civil marriage, prohibit imprisonment by private individuals
				of others to gain ransom or personal services, reward for execution of
				reactionary enemies of La Reforma, freedom of the press, grains, education,
				1862 French invasion, draft, and separation of church and state.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Victoriano Zamora, Ignacio
				Comonfort, Antonio López de Santa Anna, Juan Zuazua, José
				María Castro, Jesus Gonzalez Ortega, Manuel Gonzalez Cosio, Benito
				Juárez, José María Sanchez y Roman, Silverio Ramirez,
				Miguel Auza and Severo Cosio.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="582379c2-1d22-4765-9f8b-6064e3e844c8" type="box">4</container> <container parent="582379c2-1d22-4765-9f8b-6064e3e844c8" type="folder">4</container> 
			 <unittitle>Zacatecas (5 of 5), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">June 2, 1862 - October
				  1914</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Subjects referred to are finances, taxes, alcabalas, elections,
				salary cuts for government employees to fund the war with France, medals for
				veterans of Aculcingo and Puebla, Mexican silk, courts, judges, decretos,
				national guard, alcohol, trees, contraband, military deserters, ports, customs,
				widows must prove the death of their first spouse before remarrying, mines,
				military discipline for drunkenness, convicts sentenced to Yucatan or Baja
				California, Roman Catholic Church property, anticlericalism, honors from the
				state congress, public education of children and adults, coaches, owners of
				haciendas mandated to allow wood cutting and charcoal making on their lands,
				draft, weapons, nullify French laws, government confiscation and sale of
				traitors' property, Cinco de Mayo fiesta, identity documents for foreigners,
				right to an annual ten day fair in Mazapil, vandalism, bandits, mail, veterans,
				cavalry, prohibition of meetings of more than five, moving the capital of the
				federal government to San Luis Potosi, reduction of state functions to defense
				and security, foreign investment and colonists, pensions, treatment of French
				prisoners of war to equal treatment of Mexican prisoners of war held by the
				French, definition of traitors, government positions, resignations from
				government positions, regulations for grains and seeds, crimes by army
				personnel, pardon for military convicts, nullify decisions of French courts,
				slaughter of cattle, surrender of arms for fee paid by government, official
				mourning, abandonment of the capital by the state government, state of siege,
				suspension of government functions, release prisoners to the army, annulment of
				the state of siege, French occupation of the state, fines for using the streets
				as cloacas or communes, French holiday, sweep streets, French laws and
				regulations, interim government appointed by Juarez, money, elections, and Plan
				de Tuxtepec.</p> 
			 <p>Individuals mentioned include Severo Cosio, Benito Juárez,
				Ignacio Zaragoza, Ignacio de la Llave, Jesus Gonzalez Ortega, José Maria
				Saldierna, José M. Avila, Maximiliano, Miguel Auza, Trinidad G. de la
				Cadena, Genaro Raigosa, and Augustín López de Nava. </p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
	 </c01> 
	 <c01 level="series"> 
		<did> 
		  <unittitle>Series II: Federal Government Broadsides, 
			 <unitdate normal="1676/1910" type="inclusive">1676-1910</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="f69f0f54-5258-48e5-89d1-ae26694b306e" type="box">5</container> <container parent="f69f0f54-5258-48e5-89d1-ae26694b306e" type="folder">1</container> 
			 <unittitle>Ministerio de Fomento, Colonización, Industria y
				Comercio, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">October 15, 1823 - October 21,
				  1889</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="4ebc2624-0920-4c32-96ac-1a84fed6278f" type="box">5</container> <container parent="4ebc2624-0920-4c32-96ac-1a84fed6278f" type="folder">2</container> 
			 <unittitle>Ministerio de Hacienda (Secretaría de Hacienda) (1
				of 2), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">April 22, 1822 - October 28,
				  1828</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="81b65206-6f06-438f-b7cf-a9ee92b4eb9d" type="box">5</container> <container parent="81b65206-6f06-438f-b7cf-a9ee92b4eb9d" type="folder">3</container> 
			 <unittitle>Ministerio de Hacienda (Secretaría de Hacienda) (2
				of 2), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 28, 1829 - April 3,
				  1845</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="96ea81c8-af67-4127-99a4-5d6082025d87" type="box">5</container> <container parent="96ea81c8-af67-4127-99a4-5d6082025d87" type="folder">4</container> 
			 <unittitle>Ministerio de Justicia y Negocios Eclesiásticos, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">June 11, 1822 - July 5,
				  1835</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="8b3959c6-a270-4574-b0f8-4e86d89be8cf" type="box">5</container> <container parent="8b3959c6-a270-4574-b0f8-4e86d89be8cf" type="folder">5</container> 
			 <unittitle>Presidente de la República, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">September 17, 1828 - June 1,
				  1835</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="6a937ce1-60de-4b7c-b445-f1d40c14c382" type="box">5</container> <container parent="6a937ce1-60de-4b7c-b445-f1d40c14c382" type="folder">6</container> 
			 <unittitle>Primera Secretaría de Estado, Departamento Interior
				(1 of 2), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 19, 1827 - December
				  29, 1830</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="83c62797-9678-4806-92d1-bc5830f1f2ac" type="box">6</container> <container parent="83c62797-9678-4806-92d1-bc5830f1f2ac" type="folder">1</container> 
			 <unittitle>Primera Secretaría de Estado, Departamento Interior
				(2 of 2), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 4, 1831 - February 29,
				  1836</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="9430f663-abca-4521-a1f3-5ba7d460a8c2" type="box">6</container> <container parent="9430f663-abca-4521-a1f3-5ba7d460a8c2" type="folder">2</container> 
			 <unittitle>Primera Secretaría de Estado, Sección de
				Gobierno, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">May 24, 1822 - October 9,
				  1826</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="b65ea97c-3d15-4aeb-b9ae-680969f8eeb7" type="box">6</container> <container parent="b65ea97c-3d15-4aeb-b9ae-680969f8eeb7" type="folder">3</container> 
			 <unittitle>Primera Secretaría de Estado, Miscellaneous
				Departments, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">March 1, 1822 - May 31,
				  1910</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="7cef751f-1980-41df-97dd-b90e7753bd0b" type="box">6</container> <container parent="7cef751f-1980-41df-97dd-b90e7753bd0b" type="folder">4</container> 
			 <unittitle>Secretaría de Guerra y Marina (1 of 2), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">March 28, 1822 - September 24,
				  1828</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="8699b193-fec5-4e9e-b9f6-2c8c71a566f0" type="box">6</container> <container parent="8699b193-fec5-4e9e-b9f6-2c8c71a566f0" type="folder">5</container> 
			 <unittitle>Secretaría de Guerra y Marina (2 of 2), 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">January 28, 1829 - July 11,
				  1856</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="67f08b39-a656-4b45-8b01-3d985b243ce5" type="box">6</container> <container parent="67f08b39-a656-4b45-8b01-3d985b243ce5" type="folder">6</container> 
			 <unittitle>Mexico - Miscellaneous Offices, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">October 2, 1822 - December 12,
				  1882</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="4ac20ef4-5422-42d3-8a06-1f6e56becd0c" type="box">6</container> <container parent="4ac20ef4-5422-42d3-8a06-1f6e56becd0c" type="folder">7</container> 
			 <unittitle>Mexico - Miscellaneous Secretarías, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">August 2, 1824 - January 16,
				  1889</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		</c02> 
		<c02 level="file"> 
		  <did> <container id="a84a6e65-a8b4-479b-bac7-23ad5886b3c5" type="box">7</container> <container parent="a84a6e65-a8b4-479b-bac7-23ad5886b3c5" type="folder">1</container> 
			 <unittitle>Miscellaneous Mexican Broadsides, 
				<unitdate normal="" type="inclusive">1676 - March 8,
				  1828</unitdate></unittitle> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent> 
			 <p>Seventy-three items are located in Oversize Flat File.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		</c02> 
	 </c01>
  </dsc> 
</archdesc></ead>